<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>rini.computer</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2023-11-06T02:31:43-03:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>A quick introduction to calm technology</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2023/11/06/a-quick-introduction-to-calm-technology"/>
   <updated>2023-11-06T00:00:00-03:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2023/11/06/a-quick-introduction-to-calm-technology</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Are.na channel for further readings:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.are.na/rini/calm-technology-research-wfnzoyn9yck&quot;&gt;calm technology research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Weiser, John Seely Brown, and other technologists and anthropologists developed, at the Xerox-PARC research labs, the fundamental concepts of ubiquitous computing and calm technology. In his iconic piece, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://dl.acm.org/doi/epdf/10.1145/329124.329126&quot;&gt;The Computer for the 21st Century&lt;/a&gt;”, published in 1991, Weiser emphasizes the importance of designing “invisible technologies,” ones that blend seamlessly into the background of our everyday lives. This means technology that adapts to the environment and context in which it operates, doesn’t draw more attention than necessary and doesn’t distract a person while they execute a primary task, be it a work-related activity or a special moment with a loved one; it anticipates our needs and provides us with the right information at the right time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Amber Case describes in her book “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/calm-technology/9781491925874/&quot;&gt;Calm Technology: Principles and Patterns for Non-Intrusive Design&lt;/a&gt;,” “&lt;em&gt;An ideal app or technology is one that becomes invisible in its functioning. It provides us a utility that we need without drawing excessive attention to itself. […] Designing for calm interaction is largely a matter of finding &lt;strong&gt;nonvisual ways&lt;/strong&gt; to communicate low-priority information. […] Is primarily about presenting information in &lt;strong&gt;parallel&lt;/strong&gt;, and matching the information density of the interaction with the channel through which it communicates.&lt;/em&gt;” She gracefully describes a calm technology as elegant, humane, and unobtrusive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Case presents the principles and patterns for designing calm technologies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technology should require the smallest possible amount of attention.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technology should inform and &lt;strong&gt;create calm&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technology should make use of the &lt;strong&gt;periphery&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technology should amplify the best of technology and the best of humanity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technology can communicate, but doesn’t need to speak.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technology should work even when it fails.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The right amount of technology is the minimum needed to solve the problem.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technology should respect social norms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When diving more deeply into these concepts, she instructs about some crucial matters to be taken into consideration at the early stages of a product design: First, designers need to “&lt;em&gt;[…] decide whether your technology is a primary goal or task, or a secondary task during the pursuit of a primary goal.&lt;/em&gt;” With this definition clear, we must know how to prioritize information and delegate primary, secondary, and tertiary attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;Primary attention is visual and direct&lt;/strong&gt;—namely, the attention you might pay to the road in a car, or the attention you might pay to a desktop computer. &lt;strong&gt;Secondary attention is more distant&lt;/strong&gt;—the attention you pay to auditory signals or vibrations that do not need to be directly focused on in order to be felt. &lt;strong&gt;Tertiary consists of peripheral attention&lt;/strong&gt; such as distant sound, light, or environmental vibration. In a vehicle, primary attention is on driving, so the windshield of the car must be the primary focus at all times. The secondary information is in the rearview mirrors and side windows, as well as the feedback from the gas and brake pedals, the speedometer, and any status lights on the dashboard. The blinker function, radio, radio dial, and emergency light function all communicate tertiary information. In some cases, secondary or tertiary information might include the in-vehicle direction system.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;— Amber Case on “Calm Technology: Principles and Patterns for Non-Intrusive Design”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the website &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.calmtech.com&quot;&gt;calmtech.com&lt;/a&gt;, Case suggests some exercises that are a companion to her book and serve as practice for designing a calm tech. The first challenge is a “&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://calmtech.com/exercises.html&quot;&gt;Calmer Alarm Clock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this exercise, I will break down my process into three phases: research, references, and final concept. During the research phase, I will look into articles, books, and other media related to the project’s execution. The references will be a collection of anything that inspires me without constraints on the type of content. Finally, I will present my final design concept in the form of a graphic project that showcases the key features and functional elements of the calmer alarm clock.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
